Igor Pogorelko

email: i.pogorelko@gmail.com github: https://github.com/gruzchik

> phone: 0974946856 skype: i.pogorelko

Personal statement

Highly motivated specialist with more than 10 years of experience in IT. Good team-player easily acquiring new knowledge and grasping new technologies.

Result-oriented, proactive and responsible person. Substantial experience in system administration (Linux(Centos/Gentoo/Debian/Ubuntu) with special focus on Web and server infrastructure) and is well-familiar with various CMS-systems, development, deployment, support of websites, E-commerce engines and solutions.

Objective: DevOps Engineer

Expertise

Hosting development, configuration and administration using Apache, Nginx and MySQL, deploying Web sites on the hosting. Developing Bash and Python scripts for synchronizing of the system components, access rights management, sites back-up, etc.

Full development lifecycle support including requirements clarification and management, development, deployment and support (including SEO) of simple Web-sites using Joomla, Wordpress, Drupal, and e-commerce sites based on Virtuemart(for Joomla) and osCommerce (in general over 15 Web sites). Database configuration and support using MY SQL, MariaDB and Postgres SQL (for the Web sites developed).

Administration of Bind DNS Server, configuration and administration Postfix mail servers with support Spamassassin, Clamav etc, dhcp,proftpd, monitoring systems through snmp: mrtg, cacti. Logwatch. Version Control System using Git and SVN.

Skills

Specialties: Maintenance Engineer, Linux Administrator, Web developing, website and server scripting

Operations Systems: Debian, CentOS, Ubuntu, Gentoo, openSUSE, Red Hat, FreeBSD, Fedora, Windows Server

Programming language: PHP, Mysql, Javascript, Bash, Python, Object Pascal, HTML

Website CMS: Joomla, Wordpress, OsCommerce, Magento, Opencart

Web Servers: Apache, Nginx, lighttpd

Control Panels: Cpanel, WHM, Plesk, Virtualmin Databases: Mysql, MariaDB, Postgresql, MongoDB Monitoring systems: Nagios, Zabbix, Cacti Network file systems: NFS, GlusterFS

Virtualization: KVM, Xen, VMware Workstation, OpenVZ, LXC

Other skills: Git, SVN, Jenkins, Docker, Ansible, Node.js, iptables, LDAP, Bind, Squid, Samba, Mantis

Work experience

December 2010 – Present. System Administrator of Hosting/Deployment Engineer at UK based web ecommerce developing company

Project: infrastructure administration and support Hosting Services for IT company

Project Role: Server Administrator/Deployment Engineer

Responsibilities:

- Development of scripts using bash and python for server and infrastructure tasks, deploying them to hosts using Jenkins and Git
- Optimization of the infrastructure deployment and automation of installing the necessary packages using
 Ansible, creating a simple playbooks and roles for installation backup system to the client host, monitoring, etc.
- Creation and implementation of web solutions, servers infrastructure for necessities of customers, migration the web commerce platforms.
- Detection of SQL, XSS and other vulnerabilities on the compromised web sites, restoring and protection of website engines and web settings
- Creation, deployment and support hosting accounts based on KVM, OpenVZ, LXC system.
- Technical support of UK based customers via email, Skype and customer support system.

- Management of DNS (Bind) and mail services(Postfix, Qmail, Exim), SVN, Docker, DHCP, VPN, etc.

- Web sites development, OsCommerce, Typo3, Magento, upgrade the site functionality to the new versions of PHP, bug fixing.
- SSL Certificates registration and deployment to the websites.

Languages: Bash, Power Shell, PHP, Python, SQL

Technologies: SSL, KVM, XEN, VPN

Tools: Proxmox, Cpanel, Virtualmin, WHMCS, Ansible, Jenkins, Apache, Nginx, Zabbix, GlusterFS

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL **Source control:** SVN, Git

OS: CentOS, Debian, Ubuntu, Redhat, FreeBSD

July 2007 - November 2010. Ametrin Co Ltd, Kharkiv, Ukraine. System Administrator/Web developer.

Project: administration and support of IT infrastructure and Hosting Services

Project Role: Server Administrator/Web developer

Responsibilities:

- Establishment and further development of the hosting server (apache2 mysql proftpd) (35 sites), as well as
 writing scripts to synchronize its work and automatic backup of content separately these resources (content and
 database mysql).
- Creation, deployment and support of corporate and brand-oriented Web sites and blogs (over 15 Web sites) based on Joomla, WordPress, Slaed.
- Creation, deployment and support of ecommerce solution based on Virtuemart with additional integration with 1C system for shop items import and update, adding statistics system and SEO for the e-shop. The shop has been put in operation and brings the company stable flow of about 100 orders a month with almost no initial investments in SEO.
- Management of mail servers, Postfix Clamav Spamassasin, writing scripts in bash for solving production problems.
- Management of DNS server BIND, and LDAP, SAMBA, DHCP, VPN, configuration and traffic distribution by using SQUID, the output statistics for users on the web via lightsquid.
- Administration of local area networks and servers OS Linux Gentoo, routing, iptables, masquerading.
- Set-up of services MRTG, logwatch, the registration system applications Mantis (database Postgres), the help system based on Mediawiki.
- Administration of AD and Microsoft Exchange on Windows Server 2003.

Languages: Bash, PHP, HTML, SQL Technologies: DNS, LDAP, VPN

Tools: Apache, Nginx, Squid, Mantis, Cacti

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL

OS: Gentoo, Debian, Windows Server 2003

March 2007 - June 2007: System Administrator, «Budman» Ltd., Kharkiv, Ukraine.

Project: administration and support of IT infrastructure

Project Role: System Administrator

Responsibilities:

- Corporate Web site support (including bringing small changes into the site).
- Administration Unix / Linux.
- OS and Software installation and support.
- CCTV Videonet Support.
- Set-up, assembling and maintenance of computer and office equipment.
- Laying local telephone and network.

Languages: Bash, HTML, SQL Technologies: DNS, VPN

Tools: Squid, Monit, Apache, Mysql

OS: Fedora, FreeBSD

December 2004 - February 2007: Computer systems engineer, ISP Vokar Telecom, Kharkiv, Ukraine.

Project: ISP infrastructure support

Project Role: Computer systems engineer.

Responsibilities:

- Creation of corporate Web-sites based on PhpNuke, Slaed, site support and customization.

- Advising on configuration and use of software associated with the network and the Internet.
- Operating systems installation and configuration (Windows 98,2000, XP).
- Assembly and maintenance of computer and office equipment.
- Monitoring and remote work via ssh with routers, proxy, mail, Web and VPN-server on Linux.

Languages: Bash, PHP, HTML, SQL

Technologies: DNS, VPN

Tools: Squid, Apache, Mysql, Postfix

OS: Centos, ASPLinux, FreeBSD, Windows 2000

Education

Kharkivs'kij Nacional'nij Universytet Radioelectroniki, Kharkiv, Ukraine

Master degree in Electronics, Banking Systems Engineer, 1998-2003

Kharkivs'kij Nacional'nij Universytet Radioelectroniki, Kharkiv, Ukraine

Master degree in Economics, Engineer Economist, 2003-2005

Courses:

Professional Python Django courses in ITBursa, Kharkiv 2014-2015 L3 Linux high level. IT education center, Kiev 2016-2017

Additional Information

Languages: English (Intermediate), Russian (Native), Ukrainian (Native), Polish (elementary)

Driving License: B Category

Opportunity to work trips: Foreign passport